Uzys SMI Merge Tool http://uzys.net
Uzys 통합 자막 생성기 http://uzys.net
Fear The Walking Dead
지난 이야기
Previously on
Fear The Walking Dead
지금 퍼져있는 이 바이러스
지난 며칠의 총격, 연관이 있어
This virus that's going around, the
shootings the past few days, it's connected.
사람들이 병들어 가고
그들은 병이 들면 폭력적이게 돼
People are gettin' sick, they
get sick and they get violent.
그리고 경찰은
그들에게 총을 쏘고
And the cops shoot
them.
이런 상황에 추운 터키로
가다니 위험해요
It's dangerous for him
to go cold turkey like this.
닉이 너무 아파서
처방전이나 좀 써 달라구요
Nick is really hurting right now, and
I just need you to call in the prescription...
데리러 가고 있어
그러니 어딘지 말해
We're coming to get you,
tell us where you are.
문 닫았습니다
We're closed.
부탁입니다
여기 바깥은 안전하지 못해서요
Please, it's not safe out here.
시위대 때문에 길이 통제돼서
잠깐 버틸 장소가 필요해요
They're not letting anyone leave, we
just need somewhere to ride it out.
_
알았어요, 알았어요
Okay, okay.
사막으로 가
Go to the desert.
기다리지 말고
Don't wait.
안돼
No.
기다릴 거야
I'm gonna wait for you.
- 크리스
- 아빠!
- Chris.
- Dad!
거기서 뭘 보고 있는 거니?
What do you see out there?
그만 보라 그랬잖아
I told you to stop looking.
어떤 남자가, 그가--
엉망진창이에요, 아빠
Some guy, he was--
he was messed up, Dad.
어서 창문에서 떨어져
Just come away from the window.
- 무슨 소리였어요?
- 나도 모르지만 없어졌어
- What was that sound?
- I don't know but it's gone.
도슨씨가 크루즈네한테
무슨 짓을 한 거에요? / 그는 가버렸어
- What did Mr. Dawson do to the Cruzes?
- He's gone.
알겠는데, 대체 무슨 짓을 한거냐구요?
Yeah, but what the hell
did he do?
나도 몰라
여튼 안에 있으면 안전해, 알았니?
I don't know.
We're safe inside, okay?
오, 왜 그러니 닉
제발 그냥 삼켜봐
Oh, come on, Nick.
Please, just swallow them.
안돼요, 흡수가 너무 오래 걸려요
전 아직 무리에요
No, it takes too long to absorb.
I'm not there yet.
약을 끊으려고 먹으라는 거지 하라고--
The idea is to wean you off
of the pills, not to get--
음, 혹시 전문가세요?
Um, who's the expert?
저기, 엄마, 이거 더 있어야 해요
Hey, Mom, I need more.
안돼, 젠장. 나중에
No shit. Later.
저기, 얼마나 남았어요?
Well, how much do we have?
동쪽까지 도착할때까지는 충분해
걱정마
We have enough to get you east.
Don't worry.
- 도착하고서는요?
- 그 다음엔 달밤에 울겠지
- And then?
- And then you howl at the moon.
봐봐, 트래비스는 여기 올 거야
우린 떠날 거고
Look, Travis will be here.
We'll go.
- 그럴까요?
- 닉
- You sure?
- Nick.
분명히 온대도
He's coming.
알겠슴당
Okay.
- 돌아와
Come back.
좀 가라앉으면, 바로 움직이자
As soon as this settles
down, we move.
왔던 길로 돌아가서, 트럭에 타면
바로 가는 거야
Go back the way we came, get
to the truck, and we're gone.
그럼 매디슨 아줌마
집으로 돌아갈 거에요?
We going to go back to
Madison's after this?
- 그래
- 그냥 우리끼리 떠나면 안돼요? 그냥 우리만
- Yeah.
- Why can't we just leave? Just us.
- 크리스..
Chris...
- 젠장
Damn it.
- 그들이 쳐들어와
- 뭐?
- They're breaking in.
- Huh?
옆집에 쳐들어간다고!
They're breaking in next door.
뭐, 여긴 일단 안전하니까
여길 들어오진 않을 겁니다
Well, we're safe here.
They won't come in here.
당신이 어떻게 알아요?
How do you know?
훔칠게 뭐가 있습니까, 빗?
What are they
gonna steal, combs?
경찰이 한 시간 후면 싹
정리할 거에요, 대장님들
The police will have it sorted
in an hour, two tops.
두 시간 전에도 그랬었잖아요
You said that two hours ago.
- 전화 좀 다시 써도 될까요?
- 갖다드릴 게요
- Can I use your phone again?
- I'll get it.
감사합니다
Thank you.
어이..
Hey...
그거 갖다놔라
Put that back.
감사합니다
Thank you.
때려부셔!
Break it up!
후! 예!
Whoo! Yeah!
여기 빗뿐인줄 아시오, 네?
There's more than
combs here, you know.
압니다. 난 그저 --
I know. I was
just trying to make--
그저 자기 아들한테 다 잘 될
거라고 믿게 하려는 거죠
Make your boy believe
everything's gonna be fine.
밖에 있는 것들이
여기 들어오면 어쩌죠?
What happens if what's
out there gets in here?
도망가야죠
We run.
어디로?
Where?
서로 다른 방향으로
In different directions.
아빠
Dad.
- 아빠
- 왜?
- Dad.
- What?
- 벽이 점점 뜨거워져요
The wall's getting hot.
가야 겠어요
We've got to go.
좋아, 여기서 나갈 거야
All right, we get out of here.
떨어지지 말고
트럭으로 가
We stay close.
Get to the truck.
- 알았어
- La plata, el dinero..(귀중품, 돈..)
- Okay.
- La plata, el dinero...
떨어지면 안돼
Do not get away from me.
Vamonos(어서 가요)
Vámonos.
그래
Conmigo juntos.(내 옆에 있어)
Okay.
Conmigo juntos.
그래요, 모두 다같이
Juntas 맞죠?
Okay, everybody together.
Juntas, huh?
먼저 가요
Go ahead.
가요, 가요, 가요, 가요, 가요, 가요!
Go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
빨리
Come on.
Vamonos.(어서 가요)
Vámonos.
- 아빠?
Dad?
- 아빠!
- 이리와! 떨어져!
- Dad!
- Get over here! Stay clear.
이쪽으로
This way.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
번역 : VERONICA
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
- 진심?
- 그래
- Really?
- Yep.
- 내가 중절모
- 난 차
- I'm the top hat.
- Car.
신발
Shoe.
아빠가 항상 신발이었는데
Dad was always the shoe.
아빤 신경도 안 쓸 걸
Daddy wouldn't mind.
- 그럼 뭐 할 건데, 골무?
- 아니
- So, what do you want to be, the thimble?
- No.
- 난 차
- 차
- I'm the car.
- The car.
알았슴
All right.
고맙다. 그럼
누가 먼저 할까?
Thank you. All right,
who wants to go first?
나이 어린 순으로
Youngest to oldest.
본때를 보여주지
감이 딱 와
I'm gonna wipe the floor
with you guys. I can feel it.
이거 완전 사악한 게임이야
유치원생의 자본주의
This game's evil, dude.
Kindergarten capitalism.
맞아
Yeah.
닥치고 주사위 던져
Shut up and roll.
어이, 나 좀 올려, 임마!
Yo, pull me up, man!
- 잡았다, 짜샤
- 나 좀 올리라고!
- I got you, boy.
- Pull me up!
여기
됐다
Yo, here.
Here you go.
- 후!
Whoo!
그래, 꽉 잡아
All right, hang on.
머리 조심
Watch your head,
watch your head.
엄마!엄마!
Mama! Mama!
안돼!
Oh, no!
헉!
Oh!
- 그리젤다!
- 엄마!
- Griselda!
- Mama!
아빠!
Dad!
이봐들, 도와줘요!
도와줘요!
You guys, help!
Help!
여자가 끼었어요! 조심, 조심, 조심, 조심!
She's stuck! Be careful, be careful,
be careful, be careful!
조심해요!
Be careful!
저기 내 트럭이니
뒷문을 열어요
There's my truck.
Open the back tray.
괜찮아
괜찮아. 괜찮아
It's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
- 괜찮아
It's okay.
쇼크가 오고 있어요
You're going into shock.
자, 정신 차리고
얘기 좀 해요, 얘기 좀 해 보세요
All right, stay with me.
Talk to me, talk to me.
이봐, 어디 가는 거야?
저 놈들 잡아! 잡으라고!
Hey, where you goin'?
Get 'em! Get 'em!
덤벼봐!
우린 아무 짓도 안 했어!
Come at me!
We ain't done nothin'!
조심, 조심
엄마가 아파하잖아요
Careful, careful.
You're hurting her.
나도 알아, 미안하구나
계속 말을 걸렴
I know, sorry.
Talk to her.
의사한테 가야 해, 트래비스
We need a doctor, Trav.
젠장
Damn.
좋아, 좋아, 좋다 좋아
All right, all
right, all right.
하나, 둘, 셋, 넷
One, two, three, four,
다섯
아니, 보드워크(지명)가 요기 잉네?
Five.
And that's Boardwalk.
- 오, 젠장
- 여기 제가 사겠습니다요
- Oh, my God.
- And I will buy that, please.
알았어, 알았어
All right, all right.
- 알았다고, 보드워크 팔렸어
- 400달러
- All right, Boardwalk sold.
- $400.
- 진짜
- 이봐, 이봐
- Come on.
- Hey, hey.
진정해, 정직한 승부 하라구
Calm down, play fair.
- 은행을 그렇게 대하면 안돼
- 감사합니다
- Do not treat the banker like that.
- Thank you very much.
- 그리고 배(과일) 먹었지
- 좋은 건 맨날 지만 먹네
- And that's the pair.
- You always get all the good ones.
어, 이거봐라. 너희 다 죽었어
불쌍한 것들
Oh, look at that. I'm crushing you guys.
You're pathetic.
엄마
Mom.
일곱
Seven.
얼마나 더 기다릴 거야?
How long are we gonna wait?
- 이제 곧 잘 때야
- 퍽두, 난 잠 못자
- We can go to sleep soon.
- Yeah, I can't sleep
누가 집에 올 때까지 기다릴 때는
when I'm waiting
for someone to come home.
이거 어디서 많이 본 모습이네
Having a major case
of déjà vu right now.
11개 주 주지사들은
Governors in 11 states
비상사태를 선언하였으며
have declared
a state of emergency
주방위군의 원조를 요청했습니다
and requested the assistance
of the national guard
폭도와 시위대를 진압하기 위해..
to quell riots and protests...
무슨 일이에요, 아빠?
What's wrong, Dad?
대체 무슨 일이 난 거야?
What the hell is going on?
신원을 제대로
밝히지 않으면 떠날 수 없다
You are not able
to leave without proper clearance.
검문소가 설치되었다..
Checkpoints have been
established...
저기요?
Sir?
쏘겠다!
We will shoot!
- 숙여!
Get down!
숙이라고!
다들 괜찮아요?
뒤에도?
Everyone okay?
All right back there?
...그래서 필사적으로
도움을 필요로 합니다
...so
desperately need to get help.
시 전체에 통행금지령이 내려져 있음에도 말이지요
Despite the fact that the
citywide curfew is now in effect,
제보를 받고 있습니다..
we are still getting reports...
말 좀 걸어봐요
Talk to her.
- 플랜B는 뭐야, 라이자?
- 다른 병원
- What's plan B, Liza?
- Another hospital.
안돼요, 다 저 모양일 거에요
No, they will all be like that.
어디쯤 내려드릴까요?
Is there somewhere
I can drop you?
- 도, 돕고 싶어서요
- 내가 도와준 것처럼?
- I-I want to help.
- Like I helped you?
내가 당신을 구해줬.
그건 됐고
I just saved you from--
it doesn't matter.
- 어딘가 데려다 드릴까요?
- 우리를 데려가 주시오
- Is there somewhere I can take you?
- You will take us with you.
- 우리 집으로요?
- 네
- To my house.
- Yes.
사촌에게 전화해서 데리러 오라고 할테니
I'll call my cousin
to come and get us,
그럼 쌤쌤이잖아요
and then we will be even.
- 그런 계산 안 하셔도 되요
- 내가 먼저 시작한게 아니에요
- You can stop keeping score.
- I was not the one to start.
아빠?
Dad?
그럼, 만약에 안 돌아오면 어쩔건데요?
So, what do we do
if he doesn't come back?
6시간이나 지났어요
교통체증이 얼마나 심하기에?
It's been like six hours.
How bad can traffic be?
얘, 그는.
Well, he--
앨리샤, 가서 게임 좀 치워줄래?
Alicia, will you
go put the game away?
- 엄마, 난 진짜--
- 규칙 알잖니
- Mom, I don't really wanna--
- You know the rules,
패자가 게임을 치운다
loser puts the game away.
알았어요, 갈게요
All right, I'm going.
엄마, 밖에 있는 것들 알잖아요
여기 머물 순 없어요
Mom, you know what's out there.
We can't stay here.
- 내가 쓰레기가 되겠다는게 아니고요
- 잘됐네
- I'm not trying to be an asshole.
- Good.
- 그 남잔 전처를 데리러 갔다구요
- 아들을 데리러 간거야
- He went to get his ex-wife.
- He went to get his son.
그래요, 자기 가족
제 말은--
Yeah, his family.
I'm just saying--
우리도 그의 가족이야
그는 집에 올 거고
We're his family.
He'll come home.
이미 갔을 지도 모르죠
Maybe he went home.
이게 니가 말하는 쓰레기가
되지 않겠다는 그거니?
You know that thing you were
saying about not being an asshole?
- 엄마, 미안해요. 난 그저--
- 또 시작이야
- Hey, I'm sorry. I just don't--
- It's happening again.
- 도슨씨에요?
- 쉬.
- Is it Mr. Dawson?
- Shh.
아무것도 안 보여
I don't see anything.
좋아, 우리 모두 창문에서 떨어져요
Okay, we need to
get away from the windows.
앨리샤에게 밖에 있는게 뭔지 말해줘야죠
You need to tell
Alicia what's out there.
안돼, 아직 아무 말 없잖아
No, she hasn't
said anything yet.
그럴 필욘 없을 거야
She might not have to.
앨리샤, 이리 내려와라
Alicia, come on down here.
- 닉?
- 쉬..
- Nick?
- Shh.
열지 마!
Don't open it!
그냥 개에요
그냥 개라구요
It's just the dog,
it's just the dog.
야, 야, 야, 이제 괜찮아
Hey, hey.
Hey, it's okay.
괜찮아, 괜찮아
It's okay. It's okay.
야, 야, 야
Hey, hey, hey.
- 그게 뭐야?
- 그, 그 개 다쳤어?
What is that?
Is-- is he hurt?
이 개 피 같진 않은데
I don't think
that's his blood.
맞아, 트랜씨 집에 총이 있었지
Okay, the Trans have a gun.
샷건
당장 갖고 올게
Shotgun.
I tried to steal it once.
앨리샤, 엄마랑 떨어지지 말고
멈추지 마
Alicia, stay close.
Don't stop.
여기, 엄마. 빨리, 빨리, 빨리, 빨리
Here, Mom. Come on, come
on, come on, come on.
그래
Okay.
좋아. 따라와요
Okay. Follow me.
닉
Nick.
수잔? 패트릭?
Susan? Patrick?
- 잘됐다, 그 사람들 없네요
- 좋아
- Okay, they're not here.
- Okay.
수잔?
Susan?
- 찾았어, 찾았어요
- 오, 하느님
- I got it, I got it.
- Oh, Jesus.
음, 됐다, 탄약도 필요하니까
이거 잡아봐요
Um, okay, we need shells.
Grab that.
훠우, 조심해
이리 내놔
Whoa, careful.
Give it to me.
네
Okay.
- 그래, 이제 더 없어요?
- 몰라
- Okay, is there anymore?
- I don't know.
엄마? 엄마?
Mom? Mom?
엄마, 우리 집에 누가 있어요
Mom, someone's inside our house.
뭐?
What?
여기, 엄마
여기, 엄마, 엄마, 이거 갖고 가요!
Here, Mom.
Here, Mom, Mom, move it.
- 장전해요
- 조심해, 뒤로 물러서
- Load it.
- Watch out. Stand back.
조심해요
Careful.
- 엄마
- 쉬, 좋아, 우리 여기 있자
- Mom.
- Shh, okay, we just stay here.
그냥 여기 있자
Just stay here.
안돼, 안돼, 안돼, 안돼
No. No, no, no.
트래비스야, 안돼
It's Travis. No.
- 오 젠장
- 트래비스이면 안되는데
- Oh, my God.
- It might not be him.
그 사람 맞아. 여기, 이거 잡아요, 잡으라구요
It's him. Here,
take this, take this.
트래비스!
Travis!
매디슨
Madison.
매디?
Maddy?
- 차에 있으라고 했잖아
- 같이 있을 거야
- I asked you to wait in the car.
- We're staying with you.
아무도 없는 것 같은데요, 아빠
Looks like no one's here, Dad.
아직 차가 도로에 있어
여기 있을 거야
The car's still in the driveway.
Gotta be here.
- 왼쪽, 왼쪽, 왼쪽, 왼쪽
- 트래비스!
- Left, left, left, left.
- Travis!
- 좋아, 오른쪽, 왼쪽
- 트래비스!
- Okay, right, left.
- Travis!
- 아빠
- 물러서
- Dad.
- Get back.
트래비스?
Travis?
라이자, 크리스 데리고 차에 가
Liza, get Chris in the car now.
여기서 나가
Get out of here.
피터?
Peter?
어이, 너 병 걸렸어
Hey, you're sick.
- 피터, 정신차려 피터, 나 트래비스야
- 아빠
- Peter. Come on, Peter, it's Travis.
- Dad.
- 아빠, 무슨 짓이에요?
- 여기서 나가!
- Dad, what are you doing?
- Get out of here!
- 아빠!
- 트래비스?
- Dad!
- Travis?
트래비스!
Travis!
트래비스?
총 이리 줘
Travis?
Give me the gun.
탄약
탄약은 어디있어?
The shells.
Where are the shells?
됐어, 냅둬, 냅두고 가자
All right. Leave it, leave it.
Let's go.
트래비스, 안돼!
Travis, no!
아빠! 아빠!
Dad! Dad!
- 아빠!
- 피터! 멈춰!
- Dad!
- Peter, stop!
- 트래비스!
- 안돼, 총 내려놔!
- Travis!
- No, put the gun down!
비켜요
Move.
무슨 짓이에요?
What did you do?
살려줘요!
Help!
앨리샤, 손 이리 줘!
Alicia, give me your hand!
날 놔줘!
Get off me!
- 안돼!
- 어서 손 이리 줘!
- No!
- Just give me your hand!
- 앨리샤!
Alicia!
이-- 이것 놓으라구
Will you get--
get of me.
- 악!
- 크리스, 세상에, 무슨 일이야?
- Ah!
- Chris, God, what happened?
구해주려고 그런거잖아, 앨리샤!
I was trying
to save you, Alicia!
- 진정해
- 너 괜찮니?
- Just calm down.
- You okay?
- 아빠, 아빠나 진정해요!
- 크리스!
- Dad, you calm down!
- Chris!
수수 왜 저래요?
What's wrong
with Su-su?
수잔?
오 맙소사
Susan?
Oh, my God.
- 수잔
- 병에 걸렸어
- Susan.
- She's sick.
- 물렸어?
- 잘 안 보여
- Was she bitten?
- I can't tell.
병에 걸린게 아냐
She's not sick.
죽은 거지
She's dead.
저, 저거, 맷은 안 저렇지?
Well, that's--
that's not Matt.
그.. 그는
안 저래
He-- he's
not like that.
그는, 그는 저렇지 않다고
He-- he's
not like that.
엄마, 맷은 안 저렇다고
안 저렇다고!
Mom, Matt's not like that.
That's not him!
맷은 안 저렇다고!
That's not Matt!
왜 그런 말을 했니?
Why would you say that?
진실이니까요
Because it's the truth.
- 얘, 어디 좀 보자
- 엄마가 봐 줄 거에요
- Hey, let me see.
- Mom can fix it.
어서, 내가 코뼈 부러진 게 한두번인지 아니?
Come on. You know how many
times I've had my nose broken?
네
엄마가 봐 줄 거에요
Yeah.
Mom can fix it.
왜 그래
내가 도와줄게
Come on.
Let me help.
네
Yeah.
아우
Ow.
괜찮아..
All right...
조금만 참아
Hold on.
- 네
Yep.
부러진 것 같진 않네
I don't think it's broken.
그 남자 왜 그런 거에요 아빠?
What was wrong
with that man, Dad?
그 여자는요?
That woman?
어..
Uh...
사람들이 병들고 있어
people are getting sick.
우리도요?
Will we?
넌 괜찮을 거야
You're gonna be all right.
우리 모두 다
We all will be.
알았지?
Okay?
자, 사람들에게 얘기해 줘야지
Come on. We need
to talk to everyone.
알아요, 알아요
I know, I know.
그녀는 좀 어때?
How's she doing?
통증이 심한데 뭐 좀 없을까?
You got anything I could
give her for the pain?
아스피린보다 센 건 없지
Nothing stronger than aspirin.
음..
Um...
어, 전화기는 주방에 있어요
uh, the phone's in the kitchen
전화 필요하시면
if you need to make that call.
이미 했어요
I did.
사촌이 아침에
우릴 데리러 오겠다고 하네요
My cousin is coming to
pick us up in the morning.
어, 엄마를 침실에 좀 눕힐게, 괜찮지?
Uh, we'll set up your mom
in one of the bedrooms, okay?
- 감사합니다
- 우리도 떠나야지?
- Thank you.
- Aren't we leaving?
그래, 그래, 가야지
아침에
Yeah, yeah, we will.
In the morning.
안돼, 트래비스, 가야해
No, Travis, we have to go.
짐도 다 쌌고, 준비됐어
당신 기다리고 있었던 거야
We're packed, we're ready.
We were just waiting for you.
주방에서 얘기 좀 할까?
Can we talk about this
in the kitchen?
싫어
No.
점점 심각해지고 있어, 더 나아지진 않고
여긴 안전하지 않아
This thing's getting worse,
not better. It's not safe.
- 매디슨, 내 생각에 트래비스는--
- 됐어요, 당신 집 아니잖아요--
- Madison, I think Travis is--
- No, it's not your place--
- 나 여기 있기 싫어요, 나, 나 갈래요
- 얘..
- I don't wanna stay. I don't-- I wanna go.
- Look--
- 갈 거에요, 여기 있기 싫다구요
- 잠깐
- I wanna go. I don't wanna stay here.
- Hold on.
잠깐만. 밖은 어두워. 고속도로가
통행이 가능한 지도 모르잖아
Hold on. It is dark. We don't even know if
the freeway is passable.
- 우리가 여기 있을 거라 생각하는 거야?
- 밖에 나가면 눈뜬 장님신세야, 위험하다고
- You expect us to wait here?
- We'd be blind out there. It's dangerous.
- 여긴 안 위험하고?
- 안이잖아, 문도 잠궜고
- And this isn't?
- Inside, doors locked.
밤까지만 버티는 거야, 알았지?
We ride it out
for the night, okay?
우리 서로 돌봐야지
We'll take care of each other.
날 믿어, 매디. 아침에 떠날 거니까
Trust me, Maddy. We'll
leave in the morning.
여기 머무른다면, 피터를 돌봐야 할 줄 알아
If we're staying here, you
have to take care of Peter.
트럭에서 가스 좀 빼와야겠어요
You can get
gas from the truck.
- 왜요?
- 이 남자 태워야죠
- For what?
- To burn him.
안돼요
No.
이 남자를 태우면
병이 안 퍼지겠죠
If you burn him,
the sickness will not spread.
어떻게 퍼지는 지도 모르는 걸요
We don't know how it spreads.
이해합니다
I understand.
아는 사람이죠
You knew this man.
네
Yeah, I did.
이런 일을 겪을 사람은 아닌데
He didn't deserve this.
당신 말이 맞았어..
It's true what you said...
그들은 안 죽어
계속 돌아와
they don't die.
They keep coming back.
뭐?
What?
좋은 일이야, 지금 네가 하는 거
It's good, what you're doing,
저 여자를 돕는 일 말이야, 그리젤다를
helping that woman, Griselda.
돕는 게 아냐
I'm not helping her.
아니, 돕고 있는거야, 라이자
이제 좀 쉬어
Yes, you are, Liza.
Give yourself a break.
이미 많이 쉬었어
트래비스, 엄청 오래
I gave myself a break,
Travis, a long time.
할 수 있다고 생각했던 것보다
더 많은 것을 할 수 있단 걸 알았거든
Turns out I can do a lot more
things than I thought I could.
알아. 내 말은
나, 난 늘 알고 있었어
I know. I mean,
I-I always knew it.
아니... 넌 항상 그랬지
No... you
always said it.
7년만 있었더라면
의대를 갈 수 있었을 거고
If I had seven years now,
I could go to med school,
의사도 됐을 거라고
be a doctor.
안됐어, 그녀가 필요로 하는 게
의사인데 말이지
It's too bad, 'cause
that's what she needs.
골절은 고사하고라도
찢어진 부분이 문제야
Forget the fractures,
the lacerations.
발이 뭉개질 때, 조직이
괴사하기 시작했어
When the foot was crushed,
the tissue began to die.
조직이 곧 죽을 거고
And it will die.
피가 감염되면
Infection will poison her blood.
- 장기가 상할 거야
- 그렇게는 안 될 거야
- Her organs will fail.
- It won't come to that.
오, 그럴까?
Oh, yeah?
누가 멈춰줄건데, 니가?
Who's gonna stop it, you?
모든 걸 다 고칠 순 없어, 트래비스
Can't fix everything, Travis.
저, 있잖아?
그래도 안심이야
Well, you know what?
I'm relieved.
집에 와이프가 둘이면 어색할 것 같았는데
I thought it was gonna be awkward
having two wives in the house.
무슨 일이 난 거에요?
이게 다 뭐에요?
What's happening?
What is this?
생존을 위한 거야
Something to survive.
그래요, 그럼 내일 갈 때
이거 챙겨갈 거죠, 맞죠?
Okay, so, we should go with them
tomorrow then, right?
아니
No.
¿Donde, mama?(대체 어디로?)
¿Dónde, mamá?
무슨 일인 지도 모르잖아요
We don't know what's happening.
우리 혼자서는 감당 못해요
We can't handle this on our own.
- 내가 할 수 있어
- 아빠, 우린 도움이 필요해요
- I can handle it.
- Papa, we need help.
- 저 사람들이 도와줄 수 있잖아요
- Tsk(쯧)
- They can help us.
- Tsk.
아빠?
Papa?
빚 지고 살기엔 안 좋은 시기야
This is the wrong time
to be in someone else's debt.
그들은 우리 가족이 아냐
They are not family.
가족이라--
사촌처럼요?
Family--
like your cousin?
Oye(이녀석)
Oye.
(스페인어)어서 자요들
_
(스페인어)나도 끼워줘요
(스페인어)우리 가족 전부
엘살바도르에 묻혔다고 했잖아요
_
(스페인어)네 엄마는 도움이 필요해
(스페인어)맞아요
_
(스페인어)엄마는 아직 도움이 필요해요
(스페인어)그럼 어쩔 거에요?
_
(스페인어)진정해. 어디로 갈 지는 아니까
(스페인어)아빠..
Papa...
(스페인어)우린 그들과 같이 가야해요
_
(스페인어)우릴 늘 잘 보살펴줬잖아요
(스페인어)그를 믿어봐요
_
(스페인어)스페인어 가르치지
말자고 했던건 당신 생각이잖아
_
어이, 천사님
Hey, angel.
어디서 약을 구했어?
Where'd you get the pills?
학교로 돌아갔어
I went back to school.
경찰이 락커를 털어가진 않았거든
Cops hadn't cleared
out the locker.
똑순이
Smart girl.
닉을 사막까지 데려갈 수
있을만큼 충분히 가져올 거야
I'm gonna take enough to get
Nick set in the desert,
그리고 나머지 전부 저 여자에게 줄 거고
and then give the rest
to that woman.
그리젤다에게, 잘 생각했어
Griselda, good.
저기... 그 사람들을
데려올 수 밖에 없었어
Hey... I had
to bring them.
물론 그래야지
다쳤잖아
Of course.
She was hurt.
아냐.. 그들이 우릴 받아줬어, 매디
No... they
took us in Maddy.
대니얼이 한 행동은 유감이야
I'm sorry about what Daniel did.
그랬어야 했는걸
He had to.
당신을 잃은 줄 알았어
I thought I lost you.
아니, 안 그래
No, you didn't lose me.
절대 안 그럴 거야
You're never gonna lose me.
다신 안 떠날게
I won't leave you again.
누가 잠이 오겠어, 그치?
Who can sleep, right?
저기, 난 괜히 문제를 일으키고 싶진 않아
Look, I don't
wanna cause problems.
매디슨, 우리가 친구가 아닌 건 아는데..
Madison, I know
we're not friends...
엄마로서 말하는 거야
I'm saying this to
you as a mother.
우리 서로를 지지해줘야 해, 너와 나
We should support each
other, you and me.
애들한테 필요하니까
The kids need it.
애들을 안심시켜야 해, 그리고--
They need reassurance
right now, and--
니가 좀 해 줬으면 좋겠다
I need something from you.
아까 밖에 그 여자
수잔이란 여자야
That woman outside,
that's Susan.
내가 일하러 가면 애들을 돌봐줬어
She watched my kids
when I went to work.
남편 사별 후에는 날 돌봐줬고
Took care of me
after my husband died.
좋은 친구였겠네
Sounds like a good friend.
그랬지
She was.
그리고 내가 만약 결국 그 꼴이 된다면
And if ever I end up like her,
네가 날 돌봐줬으면 해
I need you to take care of it.
트래비스가 하게 하진 말아줘
Don't make Travis do it.
그는 망가져 버릴 거야
It would break him.
좋은 아침이에요, 수잔
Morning, Susan.
이 총열들은 실린더도 있고
These barrels
have a cylinder
총구가 좁아, 탄약이 더 넓게 퍼지라고
bore choke, for a wider
spread of the ammo.
이건 브레이크
This is the brake.
- 자, 여기 장전하는 거야. 고마워요
- Okay.
- You load here. Thank you.
이건 8번 산탄총이고
These are #8 birdshot.
이건 더블O벅이야
These are 00 buck.
그것들을 막아줄 거야
Those will stop something.
알았어요
Okay.
- 기분이 좀 나아졌어요?
- 대체 무슨 짓이신가요?
- Feeling better?
- What the hell are you doing?
그냥 총을 보여주신 거에요, 아빠
He's just showing me
the gun, Dad.
- 트럭에 짐 싸는 거 어서 마무리 해
- 별 일 아니었는데요
- Finish packing the truck.
- It's not a big deal.
크리스. 어서
Chris. Go.
남자아이들은 알면 알수록
더욱 안전해지죠
The more the boy knows,
the safer he'll be.
- 퍽두요
- 해가 될 건 없었어, 트래비스
- Uh-huh.
- I didn't see the harm, Trav.
내가 총 어떻게 생각하는 지 알잖아
You know how I feel about guns.
총은 당신 생각 쥐뿔도 안 해요
The gun doesn't care
how you feel about it.
됐어요
That's enough.
갈 준비 됐어?
We ready to go?
차에 짐 실었어, 다
Cars are loaded, yeah.
할 일이 하나 더 있어
I have one more thing to do.
수잔
Susan.
매디
Maddy.
- 매디
남편은 어디 있는걸까
I was wondering
where her husband is.
그랬음 어땠을까
Wondering what it'd been like
당신이 어젯밤 집에 돌아와서
if you'd come home last night,
이 꼴이 된 날 발견한다면
found me like this.
그가 집에 와서, 수잔이 이 꼴로..
When he comes home, finds her...
안 그렇게 됐잖아
I didn't find you like that.
패트릭은 이미 죽었을까?
You think Patrick's
dead already?
아님 그는-- 그저 떠나서
집에 돌아오지 않았던 걸까?
You think he just--
he left and never came home?
나도 모르겠어
I don't know.
그녀는 이제 뭐야?
What is she?
수잔
네 친구
Susan.
She's your friend.
- 친구니까
All the more reason.
- 그녀가 죽은 거지
- 우리도 모르지
- She's dead.
- We don't know that.
- 난 알아
- 우린 아무 것도 아직 몰라
- I do.
- We don't know anything yet.
만약 최소한의 확률로라도
What if even there's
the smallest chance
그녀가 도움받을 수 있는 거라면?
that she can be helped?
니가 결정할 일이 아니야
It's not your call.
그거 어서 나에게 줘
네가 돌이킬 수 없는 일을
Give it to me
before you do something
저지르기 전에
that can't be undone.
매디슨
Madison.
(스페인어)약해빠져서는
_
한두개만 더 줘요
I need a couple more.
엄마
Mom.
제발
Please.
- 이게 다에요?
- 그래
- Is that all we have?
- Yep.
나머진 그리젤다 다 줬어
I gave the rest to Griselda.
왜요?
Why?
필요하니까
She needs it.
엄마, 그 사람 모르는 사람이잖아요
Mom, she's a stranger.
- 아프잖아
- 나도 아파요
- She's in pain.
- So am I.
나도 알아
I know.
내가 도와줄게
I'm gonna help.
엄만 필요없어요, 엄마
약이 필요하지
I don't need you, Mom.
I need my medicine.
- 그들이 떠나고 있어요
- 잘됐네
- They're leaving.
- Good.
이건 미친짓이에요. 아빠
우리도 같이 가야 해요
This is insane. Papa, we
have to go with them.
안돼
No.
뭐가 무서운 건데요
Tell me what you're afraid of.
아무 것도
Nothing.
점점 고집만 세지네요, 피해망상 같으니
You're being stubborn, paranoid.
당신땜에 엄마가 아프잖아요
You're hurting Mama.
(스페인어)엄마와 너를 보호하는 거잖아
_
엄마는 간호사가 필요해요
She needs the nurse.
트래비스는 우리가 같이 가도
된다고 할 사람이에요
I know Travis will
let us go with him
부탁한다면
if we ask.
그들이 가고 나면, 내가
나가서 의사를 데려올 거야
Once they're gone, I will
go out, get a doctor.
- 의사가 와서 엄마를 치료해줄 거고
- 어떻게요?
- He will come and treat your mother.
- How?
어디서 의사를 찾으시려구요?
Where you gonna find a doctor?
(스페인어)네 아빠와 난
더 심한 상황에도 처해봤어
_
(스페인어)근데 아직 살아있잖니
(스페인어)엄마..
Mama...
(스페인어)그 사람들 좋은 사람들이에요
_
좋은 사람들이 제일 먼저 죽는 법이야
Good people are the
first ones to die.
- 앨리샤!
Alicia!
서둘러
이제 가야지
Come on.
We're going.
앨리샤, 어서
Alicia, come on.
- 저 귀 안 먹었어요
- 어서 가자, 응?
- I heard you.
- Let's go, huh?
쉬는 싸야죠
I had to pee.
패트릭!
Patrick!
패트릭
패트릭, 기다려요
Patrick.
Patrick, wait.
안돼
안돼, 안돼, 안돼, 안돼
No.
No, no, no, no.
수잔~ 내가 왔어~
Susan, I'm home.
공항이 폐쇄됐었어
The airport's shut down.
솔트레이크에서부터 차로 왔어
I drove all the way
from Salt Lake.
전화하려고 했는데, 근데--
I tried
to call you, but--
- 수잔?
- 패트릭! 패트릭!
- Susan?
- Patrick! Patrick!
만지면 안돼요
Don't touch her.
이제 당신 아내가 아니에요
That's not your wife.
- 무슨 일이야, 수잔?
What happened, Susan?
- 성함이 어떻게 되십니까?
- 어, 트래비스 마나와
- What's your name, sir?
- Uh, Travis Manawa.
- 여기가 댁의 집인가요?
- 네, 제 애인 집입니다
- This is your residence?
- Yes, my girlfriend's house.
- 성함이 어떻게 되시죠, 여성분?
- 매디슨 클락
- And what's your name, ma'am?
- Madison Clark.
- 거주자는 몇 명이죠?
- 음, 아홉.. 전부 아홉이요
- How many occupants?
- Um, nine-- nine altogether.
대가족이시네요
Big family.
어, 이름, 부탁합니다
트래비스 마나와
Uh, names, please?
I got Travis Manawa
그리고, 어, 매디슨 클락
and, uh, Madison Clark.
어, 니콜라스 클락
앨리샤 클락
Uh, Nicholas Clark,
Alicia Clark,
엘리자베스 올티즈
크리스토퍼 마나와
Elizabeth Ortiz,
Christopher Manawa.
음..
Um...
대니얼 살라자
그리젤다 살라자, 오필리아 살라자
Daniel Salazar, Griselda
Salazar, Ofelia Salazar.
알겠습니다, 가족
모두 안에 있도록 해 주세요
Okay, make sure that
everyone in your family stays inside.
저희 이웃, 패트릭 트랜 씨를
어디로 데려가시는 건가요?
Can you tell me where you took
my neighbor, Patrick Tran?
이웃분께서는 감염된
피를 뒤집어쓰셨습니다
Your neighbor was covered
in the infected's blood.
아내의 피였는데요
It was his wife's blood.
더이상 그의 아내는 아니었지요
That wasn't his wife anymore.
그거 전염되는 겁니까, 그 피가?
그게 이렇게 된 원인입니까?
Is it contagious, the blood?
Is that how it happens?
당신 혹은 집 안 누군가 노출된 적 있나요?
Have you or anyone in
this house been exposed?
아니요
No.
그건 뭡니까?
What's that?
저희 개가 죽었습니다
Our dog died.
유감이네요
Sorry to hear that.
여러분, 안으로 들어가십시오
Folks, get back inside.
저희가 가겠습니다
We will come to you.
브라보 2, 브라보 2
Bravo two, bravo two.
기갑부대가 도착했네
The cavalry's arrived.
이제 점점 나아질 거야
It's gonna get better now.
¿Que pasa?(무슨 일이십니까?)
¿Qué pasa?
_
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
번역 : VERONICA
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com